Weiss, Murray; Papers apap338
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Murray Weiss Papers
1951-1961
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap338
0.33 cubic ft.
The Murray Weiss Papers contain photographs taken during Weiss' tenure as a counselor and swimming instructor at Camp Woodland.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Murray Weiss donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections in 2013.
Biographical Sketch
Murray Weiss was born in 1926 in New York City. He was a counselor and swimming instructor at Camp Woodland in Phoenicia, New York, under the direction of Norman Studer. Weiss often photographed campers and camp guests. He also took pictures of local residents and landscapes.
A photographer for more than 60 years, Weiss' work is featured in a number of galleries and museums including the Milwaukee Art Museum and the Philadelphia Museum of Art. He also spent many years as a professor and lecturer, most notably at the Philadelphia University of Art. He was founder of the Milwaukee Center for Photography. He passed away in February 2016 and was survived by his wife Teri, three daughters, and four grandchildren.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes photographs and negatives taken by Mr. Weiss during the 1950s and 1960s at Camp Woodland. Weiss' negatives and prints depict events, like the Folk Festival of the Catskills, Sunday meetings at camp, and field trips. Weiss captured visitors to the camp on film, including Pete Seeger, Red Thunder Cloud, and Bessie Jones, as well as area Catskill residents.
For additional information about and photographs of Camp Woodland, please see the Norman Studer Papers, APAP-116.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Music; Folklore; Camps--New York (State); Folk festivals--New York (State); Black-and-white photographs; Negatives (photographic); Weiss, Murray; Studer, Norman; Camp Woodland
- Duloff's, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 1)
- Harry Siemsen, 1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 2)
- Postmistresses, 1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 3)
- Quarry, Sawkill, and Mr. Oakley at Hurley, 1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 4)
- Orson Slack, 1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 5)
- Mary Kiersten, 1952 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 6)
- Hunt, a Raftsman, 1953 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 7)
- Woodland Museum, Mike Todd, 1953 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 8)
- Various Camp Activities, 1955 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 9)
- Camp Woodland Festival Cantata, 1958 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 10)
- Sunday Meetings, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 11)
- Olympics, Work Campers, Junior Camp, and Drug Union Kids, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 12)
- Cooperstown Farmers' Museum Field Trip, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 13)
- D & H Canal and Work Campers' Bike Trip, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 14)
- Hikes with Norman Studer, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 15)
- Hoop Shaving Sheds, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 16)
- Various Landscapes and Locations, 1961 (Box 1 (Murray Weiss Papers ), Folder 17)